Leave your inhibitions at the door... the show is about to begin.
Showgirls is a drama film directed by Paul Verhoeven.
Fresh to Las Vegas with no connections, Nomi Malone
takes a job as an exotic dancer.
Her talents are quickly noticed by Cristal, a headlining dancer
who senses an opportunity to bolster her own act.
But Nomi won’t play second fiddle and soon begins her venomous path to the
top, ruthlessly backstabbing anyone who gets in her way.
Nomi Malone, played by Elizabeth Berkley.
Zack Carey, played by Kyle MacLachlan.
Cristal Connors, played by Gina Gershon.
James Smith, played by Glenn Plummer.
Al Torres, played by Robert Davi.
Tony Moss, played by Alan Rachins.
Showgirls is a 1995 erotic drama film directed by Paul Verhoeven, written by Joe Eszterhas, starring Elizabeth
Berkley, Kyle MacLachlan, Gina Gershon, Glenn Plummer, Robert Davi, Alan Rachins, and Gina Ravera.
The film focuses on an ambitious young woman hitching a ride to Las Vegas to
pursue her dreams of being a professional dancer and showgirl.
Produced on a then-sizable budget of around $45 million, significant controversy and hype
surrounding the amounts of sex and nudity in the film preceded its theatrical release.
In the United States, it was rated NC-17 for "nudity and erotic sexuality throughout, some graphic language, and sexual
violence." Showgirls was the first (and to date only) NC-17 film to be given a wide release in mainstream theaters.
Distributor Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (MGM) dispatched several hundred staffers to theaters across North America playing Showgirls to ensure
that patrons would not sneak into the theater from other films, and to make sure filmgoers were over the age of 17.
Audience restriction due to the NC-17 rating, coupled with poor reviews, resulted in the film
becoming a box-office bomb, grossing just $37.8 million against a budget of $45 million.
Despite a negative theatrical and critical consensus, Showgirls enjoyed success on the home video/VHS
market, generating more than $100 million from video sales, allowing the film to make a profit.
Since its video release, Showgirls has gone on to become one
of MGM's top twenty all-time bestsellers.
For its home video release, Verhoeven prepared an R-rated edition for
rental outlets that could not (or would not) carry NC-17 films.
The R-rated edit runs about three minutes shorter,
omitting some footage deemed to be more graphic.
This version was later also available on television
networks, such as HBO and In Demand (Pay Per View).
Showgirls was universally panned upon its cinematic release, and is still
consistently ranked as one of the worst films of all time.
In the 21st century, it has come to be regarded as a cult film, with a dedicated fanbase; Showgirls has also been subject to
critical re-evaluation, with some notable directors and critics considering it a serious satire worthy of praise.
The film explores themes of dancing, go-go dancer,
striptease, spanner, affectation.
The tone is emotional.